SYLENS: The moment they see you, Hades will too.
SYLENS: He'll issue another kill order, and this time
the entire Shadow Carja military will be after you.
So disable their Focuses, you've done it before.
SYLENS: It's not that simple.
SYLENS: Too many Focuses in one place, each of them
communicating with each other and back to Hades.
A whole network of them.
"Network" — what's that?
Er, imagine a vast, invisible web stretched across the land
from end to end, connecting Focuses together.
Allowing them to communicate over vast distances instantaneously.
Alright, so is there some way to cut the web down?
Hmm. Crash the network? Audacious!
Yes, there is a way, a weak point in the network.
Point the way.
I'll send the location data to your Focus.
Head there, and I'll be in touch when you're close with more directions.
Keep things quiet.
CARJA: It's not what I imagined when I was a boy, but it's decent work…
You're not—
Here they come.
SHADOW CARJA: Only the Carja in Shadow truly deserve the name Carja.
Hello!
These are something special.
Steady now, give me a second.
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: Aloy, you're very close now.
ALOY: I was wondering when you would speak up.
SYLENS: There's a sheer rock wall just ahead.
SYLENS: Look close and you'll find handholds leading up.
ALOY: Oh really? And who put those there, hmm?
ALOY: Right, why would I expect an answer?
ALOY: It's so much more exciting to keep it all a mystery.
ALOY: "Crash the Eclipse Focus network", he said.
ALOY: So how are we gonna do that?
ALOY: Oh wait, I forgot. "We" won't, I do all the dangerous stuff.
ALOY: You just listen in.
ALOY: Alright, what now?
SYLENS: We wait, that's what.
SYLENS: Take a seat at the campfire and rest.
SYLENS: When night falls we'll talk.
ALOY: At least I'll have a fire to keep me company.
ALOY: I wonder where the path through that crevice leads.
How nice of you to finally drop by.
Our purpose this night is to crash the Focus network.
Yeah, tell me the part I don't know. How?
For starters, you'll need to infiltrate the Eclipse's main base.
ALOY: Wait, what?
SYLENS: That's right.
SYLENS: Fortunately for you, I brought you around to the back way.
SYLENS: It's right through that crevice.
SYLENS: Once you reach the base, you'll see the objective.
SYLENS: A derelict Tallneck that's been extensively modified.
SYLENS: Climb the Tallneck, grafted into the top of its disc
you'll find a module of sorts.
SYLENS: Destroy that and the Focus network will crash.
ALOY: So you were part of the Eclipse?
SYLENS: I've never been part of anything.
SYLENS: I serve my own interests always.
SYLENS: But … it is the case that I …
SYLENS: … assisted the Eclipse before I sensed the threat they might become.
SYLENS: It was a mistake that I'm doing what I can to correct.
ALOY: What sort of assistance did you give them?
SYLENS: Head through that crevice, Aloy.
SYLENS: You have more important things to do than ask questions.
Hrrmph.
ALOY: Gonna be tight.
ALOY: Corrupted machines, patrolling like guards.
SYLENS: More like soldiers, held in reserve for a war yet to come.
SYLENS: You'll have to get past them.
ALOY: This is the easy way in?
SYLENS: The back way. I didn't say it'd be easy.
ALOY: Explosions in the distance.
SYLENS: Pay them no mind, doesn't concern you.
ALOY: I'll find a use for you.
SYLENS: Getting close now, head for that ridge.
SYLENS: The Tallneck's just over this ridge.
SYLENS: You'll see it when you reach the top.
SYLENS: Now be ready to act fast.
SYLENS: We need to get in and get it done before they raise an alarm.
SYLENS: Here we go.
ALOY: You getting this?
ALOY: I see the legs of a Tallneck down there, but no Tallneck.
SYLENS: Damn, the transmitter's been moved.
SYLENS: Check down the ravine to the left, only place it could be.
ALOY: So much for your insider knowledge. Toward the explosions, great.
SYLENS: You've got exactly one shot at this, Aloy.
SYLENS: So spare the sarcasm and make it count.
SYLENS: You see that bridge over the ravine?
ALOY: Yep.
SYLENS: Memorise its location, there's a rappel point on the side.
SYLENS: That'll be your way out.
ALOY: And these Eclipse troopers?
SYLENS: Avoid them. Or kill them, your choice.
SYLENS: The blasting should cover any noise you make.
SYLENS: Find the Tallneck and destroy the module on top.
ALOY: Here we go.
ECLIPSE: It's been weeks since Helis was around. What's he been up to?
ECLIPSE: Terrifying someone I'm sure.
ECLIPSE: The pain of our labour will birth a new reign, a righteous one.
ECLIPSE: Something over here!
ALOY: Still sniffing around.
ECLIPSE: Contact!
ECLIPSE: We're dead too if you don't fight!
ECLIPSE: Can't afford any more losses, fight!
ECLIPSE: Bleed for the Shadow!
ECLIPSE: Farewell, fool.
ALOY: Is there fighting up ahead?
SYLENS: No, it's a mining operation.
SYLENS: So long as you're quick it won't affect you.
ALOY: Oh good, another secret.
ALOY: Fresh as it comes.
ALOY: What is this place?
SYLENS: A distraction.
ALOY: There are several datapoints.
ALOY: A mural of Meridian and the Spire.
ALOY: This armour, there's only one man big enough to wear this. Helis.
ALOY: This is his shelter? Not exactly fancy.
SYLENS: What would you expect of a fanatic?
SYLENS: His only extravagance is his brutality.
ALOY: So you know him?
SYLENS: Just enough to want to stop him.
HELIS: When sleep refuses to come, I think of our wedding night.
HELIS: How you welcomed me to the marital bed.
HELIS: How after, when you fell asleep, I lay there watching your delicate face.
HELIS: For all its beauty I detested its fragility.
HELIS: A rage swelled up inside me.
HELIS: I abhored that bed, how its softness threatened to swallow us up.
HELIS: And that room, the stench of incense,
the fine embroidery, the drapes — all of it, weak.
HELIS: I slipped from the bed, threw open the casement,
and lay naked on the stone floor, determined to spurn all seductions of comfort.
HELIS: But when I woke the next morning,
you lay beside me, naked as I in the cold.
HELIS: Your body stretched beside mine seem chiselled from stone.
HELIS: I saw you wake, instantly alert, like an animal ready to strike.
HELIS: You said nothing, you did not have to.
HELIS: Already you had shown me beyond doubt that we were meant to be.
HELIS: Never does the Sun show pity.
HELIS: And yet, when my wife died in birthing,
and in dying ended the life of my child unborn, I pitied myself.
HELIS: My Lord sensed this.
HELIS: But instead of casting me down for weakness,
he cast upon me a radiant beam of honour.
HELIS: He ordered my kin buried
in the sacred caves reserved for royals and heroes.
HELIS: Unimaginable.
HELIS: Never again would I doubt that I am the chosen of the Sun.
HELIS: Never again would pity find a place in me.
HELIS: Not for myself, or another.
HELIS: When I first set eyes on the Buried Shadow I trembled.
HELIS: Was I not the chosen of the Sun?
HELIS: A blazing light of faith to shred and scatter darkness?
HELIS: Was it not my place to destroy this devil?
HELIS: But High Priest Bahavas instructed me
in the prophecy and set right my frame of mind.
HELIS: The murder of the true Sun-King broke the cosmic cycle short of completion.
HELIS: A whole world cast into darkness, doomed.
HELIS: To resume and turn the wheel of time
would require more than Sun and faith.
HELIS: All forces must combine, all halves of nature join to one cause.
HELIS: Shadow to sun, night to day.
HELIS: Even a Buried Shadow wants the wheel to turn.
HELIS: For without a sun in the sky, there can be no shadow.
HELIS: My Lord, the thirteenth king of the Carja Sundom was murdered.
HELIS: Cut down by cowards who mistook firm rule for madness.
HELIS: "Ever the strong are beset upon by the weak."
HELIS: So he said, as the traitors launched their assault.
HELIS: As their cannons forged by Oseram filth
toppled the battlements and burst the gates.
HELIS: I would have fought to the end.
HELIS: But it was his will, the will of the Sun,
that I lead the prince and queen into the west to safety.
HELIS: My Lord did not hesitate. He saw his fate.
HELIS: He looked into the Sun, and he did not blink.
HELIS: With me he sent kestrels, nobles, Sun Priests, and slaves.
HELIS: Killing all that stood in the way, I carved a path to Sunfall.
HELIS: There we joined others to gather the strength to take back our home.
HELIS: But our strength only faded, until the Buried Shadow was brought to light.
HELIS: Every morning I wake to the same nightmare, the same reality.
HELIS: Holy Meridian in the hands of profligates, debased.
HELIS: The Spire, towering above the horizon,
like in a glittering spike through the centre of my mind.
HELIS: Every daybreak in exile is a mark of failure, but the count of days runs thin.
HELIS: I will see Meridian retaken, the profligates slaughtered,
a true king restored to the mesa throne.
HELIS: In this I have become an instrument of prophecy.
HELIS: So long as King Itamen languishes at Sunfall coddled by his mother,
he will never learn the true lessons of the Sun.
HELIS: I have tried to instruct him,
but the shadow of his mother's influence is upon him.
HELIS: I took him to the palace balcony
to behold an offering of sacrifice in the ring.
HELIS: But he showed no thirst for it.
HELIS: He averted his gaze.
HELIS: "Look to the Sun", I told him.
HELIS: "Do not shield your eyes. In all things it is absolute."
HELIS: "One day it nurtures life, and the next scorches life away."
HELIS: "It burns the skin of champions and wretches alike."
HELIS: "Never does the Sun show pity."
HELIS: "That is the example a Sun King must follow, the example of your father."
HELIS: But before my instruction could take hold, she was there.
HELIS: Clutching him to her robes, burying his face against her breast.
HELIS: How is a king to rule, when he cannot even see?
ALOY: Did it!
ALOY: He's a fanatic alright, single-minded.
SYLENS: It gives him a focus that you seem to lack.
SYLENS: Now, how about finding that Tallneck?
ALOY: Would not have been easy to drag a Tallneck down this path, why bother?
SYLENS: Just find it and get to the top.
SYLENS: Destroy the module and then get out, fast as you can.
ALOY: Sure is a lot of blasting up there, sounds busy.
SYLENS: Busy enough not to notice you, let's hope.
ALOY: I see it.
ALOY: They've built some kind of structure around it.
SYLENS: Climb it, the sooner this is done, the better.
ALOY: I don't like this, feels wrong.
SYLENS: Everything here is wrong, just get to the module and destroy it.
ALOY: What's this? A signal.
FOCUS: Alert. Irregular transmission source detected.
ALOY: I see the module.
SYLENS: Good. Now be quick.
ALOY: This … this is Hades?
SYLENS: Aloy, this is not the time.
ALOY: It's a Metal Devil.
SYLENS: Open the module's casing, now.
SYLENS: ALOY! Do as I say, or all is lost!
HADES: Entity has come here?
HADES: Entity miscalculated.
HADES: Entity cannot destroy me, I am beyond its reach.
ALOY: Maybe you are, but this isn't!
HADES: Destroy the entity!
ALOY: Ugh, what?
SYLENS: Keep moving!
ALOY: Yeah, you think?
SYLENS: Keep moving! KEEP MOVING!
ALOY: Talk about a "brave" trail.
ALOY: Almost there!
SYLENS: Keep running!
ALOY: What do you think I'm doing, taking a nap?
ALOY: Oh, come on!
SYLENS: Head left, towards the camp!
SYLENS: The whole base is on high alert.
ALOY: Yeah, I noticed!
ECLIPSE: I missed!
ALOY: Are you kidding me?
SYLENS: Run, don't fight!
ALOY: Bridge in sight!
SYLENS: That's the way out!
ALOY: I know!